cnh.com 2009-05-07

# CNH >> Privacy Policy

CNH Global N.V. has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: CNH.com. 

Your IP address is used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. We use small text files to deliver content specific to your interests. Each text file is encrypted for your security. 

Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information (like their name and email address). We use customer contact information from the registration form to send the user promotional material from some of our partners. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. 

This site contains links to other sites. www.cnh.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect visitor's contact information (like their email address). Contact information from the order form is used to send orders, information about our company, and promotional material from some of our partners to our customers. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. 

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like their email address). The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. We run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (like their email address). The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. 

**Public Forums**  
This site may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

**Security**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

**Children's Guidelines**  
Our Web site meets the guidelines of TRUSTe's Children's program and we will: 

  * NOT collect online contact information without prior parental consent or parental notification, which will include an opportunity for the parent to prevent use of the information and participation in the activity. Without prior parental consent, online information will only be used to respond directly to the child's request and will not be used for other purposes without prior parental consent. 
  * NOT collect personally identifiable offline contact information without prior parental consent. 
  * NOT distribute to third parties any personally identifiable information with out prior parental consent. 
  * NOT give the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable contact information without prior parental consent. 
  * NOT entice by the prospect of a special game, prize or other activity, to divulge more information than is needed to participate in the activity. 

**Safe Harbor**  
Policy # Legal - 13.02 EFFECTIVE DATE: January 01, 2002 

**A. PURPOSE**  
CNH is committed to providing privacy protection of employee data that is maintained by the company. It is the Company's intention to comply with all local data protection regulations worldwide including the European Commission's Directive on Data Privacy. The company will certify annually with the U.S. Department of Commerce that CNH is in compliance with the safe harbor framework approved by the European Union. Compliance with the safe harbor framework demonstrates the adequate privacy protection required by the European Commission's Directive. 

**B. SCOPE**  
This policy applies to all employees of CNH Global N.V., and its subsidiaries. 

**C. INTRODUCTION**  
CNH maintains a global Human Resources Management System (HRMS) to manage and administer the Company's human resources data storage. The database for the HRMS is located at the Company's data center in Italy, which is maintained by an affiliate of the Company. The system provides a benefit to the company and employees and is used to support payroll, benefits, and bonuses, improve training programs, plan career development, monitor workplace health and safety, and supports the company goal of being the "best place to work." 

**D. POLICY**  
Notice: Employees are asked to provide personal data at hiring, and throughout their employment, for the purpose of compensation including fringe benefits and other tasks related to the operation of the company. Employees may request to review their personal information maintained in the HRMS by contacting the Human Resource Representative for their location. Employees should direct any inquiries or complaints, regarding personal data, to their local HR Representative. 

Choice: There are situations when personal data are transmitted to third parties to provide compensation, fringe benefits, or to satisfy home country government reporting requirements. Prior written consent of employees will not be requested for this employment-related data. CNH will not provide personal data to any other third party without the prior written consent of the employee. 

Onward Transfer: If personal data is transferred to third parties acting as an agent for the company, such third party will be required to either subscribe to the safe harbor principles or enter into a written agreement with CNH requiring the third party to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the relevant principles. 

Security: Access to the HRMS is controlled by a log-on sequence and requires all users to identify themselves and provide a password before access is granted. Users are limited to data required to perform their job function. Security features of the HRMS software and developed processes are used to protect personal information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. 

Data Integrity and Access: Employee data maintained by the company will be used for the sole purpose of supporting company operations and providing employee benefits. Company HR and Payroll processes include tasks and procedures to keep personal data accurate, complete, and current. Employees have the option to review personal data by contacting their local HR representative. As part of the review process, employees can correct, amend, or delete that information where it is inaccurate. 

Enforcement: Annual reviews of this policy and principles will take place as part of the certification process with the U.S. Department of Commerce. CNH will include internal compliance reviews as part of the company internal audit process. Employees should forward any complaints or disputes regarding personal data protection to their local HR Representatives. Complaints or disputes that cannot be remedied by the local HR Representative should be forwarded to the Office of Corporate Secretary located at: 

  * Attn: Office of Corporate Secretary  
6900 Veterans Boulevard  
Burr Ridge, Illinois 60527  

CNH agrees to cooperate with (local country) data protection authorities to resolve disputes with employees that cannot be remedied directly with the employee. 

The Company has the authority to change or terminate this policy in whole or in part and to change or discontinue the type and amount of benefits offered by this policy and the eligibility rules at any time, without prior notice to or the consent of any employee or other person having a beneficial interest in the policy. Similarly, the Company retains its sole and absolute discretionary authority to resolve all questions arising in the administration, interpretation and application of this policy. This authority includes construing the terms of this policy, including any disputed or doubtful terms, and determining the eligibility of any individual to participate in this policy or to receive any policy benefit. The Company's determination will be conclusive and binding on all persons. This policy does not constitute a contract of employment with CNH, or any of its subsidiaries. 

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor. This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service. You can send email to [nacustomerrelations@cnh.com](mailto:nacustomerrelations@cnh.com)

**Correct/Update**  
This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided. Email: [nacustomerrelations@cnh.com](mailto:nacustomerrelations@cnh.com)

**Contacting the Web Site**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact: Customer Relations [nacustomerrelations@cnh.com](mailto:nacustomerrelations@cnh.com)
